JUAN PABLO CORTEZ

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+593-9956-20202

juanpacortexz93@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/juanpacortexz93/

Occidental St. & Fernandez Salvador, Quito - Ecuador

EDUCATION

Ing. en Electrónica y Telecomunicaciones

Escuela Politécnica Nacional

2021

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native), English (B1), German (A1) & French (A1).

MY SKILLS

Consider the following scale: Talent (1-2), Junior(3-4), Medium(5-7) & Senior(8-10)

- SCRUM (Medium) & Design Thinking (Medium)
- HTML Basics: Figma (Junior), HTML5 (Senior), SaaS & CSS (Medium), Bootstrap (Medium), Javascript (Medium), Typescript (Medium) & JQuery (Medium)
- Backend: C# (Medium), Node.Js (Medium).
- Frameworks & Libraries: .NET Core (Medium) & Angular (Medium).
- .NET Core: WPF (Junior), Entity Framework, API Web (Medium), MVC Web Applications (Medium) & Blazor WebAssembly (Junior)
- Auth: OpenID, Oauth2 & JWT
- Testing: NUnit y xUnit (Junior).
- SQL Databases: MS SQL (Medium), MySQL (Medium) & PostgreSQL (Junior)
- NoSQL Databases: Firebase (Realtime & Firestore) (Junior) & MongoDB (Junior)
- Azure: Cloud (Medium) & DevOps (Medium)
- Excel (Medium) & PowerTools (Junior)
- Soft Skills (Senior).

PROFILE

I am a developer in continuous learning with a four-year trajectory and specialized in Full Stack using C# and JavaScript, complemented by knowledge in Data Science and IoT. My objective is to provide effective solutions to the client, based on their economic and infrastrutucture possibilities, the best technologies and frameworks like React.JS, Angular & .Net Core, and the use of agile methodologies such as SCRUM or Design Thinking. In addition, my soft skills have been trained me to help lead work groups and be a positive member in decision-making processes and the work environment.

.....

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

COMPUTER SOLUTIONS EAST (US / INDIA)

October, 2023 - January, 2024

Computer Solutions East - Human Resources Management Website

 BambooHR replica with some new features created for CSE Human Resources Team. Language used: C#. Frameworks: .NET. Types: MVC y API Web. Relational Database Language: Microsoft SQL. Relational Database Program: Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio 2019.

Software Developer Level 1

CAPMATION (UNITED STATES)

October, 2022 - June, 2023

Automotive Parts Solutions Team @ APS team - Phase 1

- Creation of Azure HTTP Trigger repricing functions for parts daily evaluation.
 Language used: Python. Key libraries used: SQLAlchemy, Numpy, and Pandas.
 Relational Database Language: Microsoft SQL. Relational Database Program:
 Microsoft SSMS 2019. Cloud platform used: Azure & DevOps.
- Bid Buddy and Bidding System 2 systems analysis and refactoring. Project type: Web Developer. Language used: C#. Framework: .NET.MVC. Relational Database Language: Microsoft SQL. Relational Database Program: Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio 2019. Additional programs and resources used: Visual Studio 2019, IIS, and Word.
- APS's Phase 1 Docs & Workflows: UAT, Repricing Requirements, and User's Manual Docs. Language docs: EN.

Engineering Mananger and Full Stack WebDev Developer

ITECH - Integrador de Tecnología CIA. LTDA.

March, 2021- September, 2022

- miPercha (hardware and software): Creation of low-power electronic price tags with ESP8266 microcontrollers More information about the project is reserved for security reasons. Tools used: CPanel, HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, MySQL & Arduino.
- milD (software): Real-time inventory control using Zebra RFID technology, which
 can be viewed from a website. Used by Association of Municipalities of
 Ecuador. Tools used: CPanel, HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP,
 MySQL, and Java.
- miOptica (Software): commerce management website. Languages, databases, and frameworks used: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, and MySQL.
- Engineering Management: Interinstitutional internship contracts with the Academia (Escuela Politécnica Nacional). Renewal of the Partnership Program with Zebra.

CODING SKILLS

- Algorithms & Data Structures (Medium)
- SOLID Principles (Medium)
- Arquitectures: Client-Server, Model-View-Controller, Hexagonal & Serverless.
- Design Patterns (Medium)
- Microservices (Medium)
- Another programming languages that I used in my professional carreer: Arduino, Python (Web, Data Science and AI), PHP (Web Programming) & JAVA (Web API's).

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Coding: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Google Collab, Anaconda, PyCharm y Eclipse.
- Web API's: Postman & ThunderClient (VS Extension)
- Databases: SQLite3 Console, SSMS2019, PgAdmin, MySQL Workbench, MySQL PHPMyAdmin, Firebase & MongoDb Atlas.
- Docs Control Version: Git & GitHub
- · Documentation: Notion and SharePoint
- Communication: Teams & Slack

COURSES

- CISCO NETACAD Python Essentials 2 & Python Essentials 1. (PCAP-31-0x Certification Exam Courses)
- Platzi "Curso de FastAPI: Introducción, Operaciones, Validaciones y Autenticación."
- Platzi "Audiocurso para Prevenir el Burnout en tu Empresa"
- Platzi "Curso de Design Thinking con Minds Garage"
- Platzi "Fundamentos de Arquitectura de Software"
- Platzi "Curso de Fundamentos de Bases de Datos"
- Platzi "Curso de Introducción a C# con .NET 3.1"

Important: You can check out all of my certifications and courses in my LinkedIn Profile (70 without English Certifications).

WORK EXPERIENCE

"Proceso de contratación No. 025-IC"

QUITO TURISMO (ECUADOR)

December, 2021

This public contract was awarded to the best presented offer and consisted of the preventive physical and logical maintenance of 10 electronic devices (PCs, servers, and storage systems) at the Quito Turismo Data Center in Quito, Ecuador. The report for this work was approved on December 21st by Engineer Fabricio Medina, the contract administrator for the minimal amount contract 025-IC.

Technical Maintenance Intership

DGIP - EPN (ECUADOR)

April, 2019 - October, 2019

I won a competition based on merit and opposition, which allowed me to participate in a 6-month internship program at my university. Using the OTRS ticketing system, I provided preventive and reactive maintenance for various types of equipment (PCs, laptops, printers, Infocus devices, VoIP telephony, networks, and structured cabling) for administrative and teaching staff, as well as laboratories and classrooms. All these processes were documented according to the institution's internal regulations. Additionally, I was able to manage inventories, including the decommissioning or proper documentation process for equipment donated by the United Nations for educational programs in Ecuador, specifically benefiting the Escuela Politécnica Nacional.

Cibersecurity Intership

DGIP - EPN (ECUADOR)

April, 2018 - June, 2018

I was part of the cybersecurity department at Escuela Politécnica Nacional, where I was involved in implementing preventive actions and maintaining the computer security policy manual of the university. Additionally, I received training in ISO 27001 standards for information protection at both the logical and physical levels.

FUN FACTS ABOUT ME:

- In my free time, I work as a part-time professor (on weekends). For the past 10 years, I have been teaching students ranging from 11 to 27 years old, covering subjects from high school to university, including master's and doctoral programs. My favorite subjects to teach are Maths, Physics, and Programming.
- I love playing soccer, swimming, traveling, eating, and meeting new people and cultures. However, I can adapt easilly to remote work.
- During my free time, I am electronic music producer. You can listen to my music and follow me on Spotify or Instagram under the name State Of 93.
- From 2018 to 2020, I had the opportunity to contribute as an opinion writer, interviewer, and researcher for Bassmusic, the number one hardstyle music magazine in the Spanish-speaking world. This experience allowed me to develop skills in social communication.